Sarita Rawat

A-126, Alaknanda Enclave, Rampark, Loni, Ghaziabad, U. P. -201102 9555520568 | saritarawat8420@gmail.com

Profile Summary

• Positive, passionate & confident Human Resource professional with 4.9 years of experience in **HR Operations**, **Payroll**, **Administration**, **Compensation & Benefits and Employee Welfare**.

Expertise in Employee Relations, Onboarding & Offboarding, Payroll Processing, HRIS, MIS Reporting, Induction, Statutory Compliance, Attendance Management, Team work & Collaboration.

An effective communicator with good analytical, interpersonal skills, planning, multi-tasking and problemsolving skills. Strong belief in continuous & consistent improvement in order to enhance skills & broaden horizons.

Committed to driving HR initiatives that align with business objectives and promote employee engagement.

Experience

ScaleneWorks People Solutions LLP

13th April 2022 - 25th August 2023

HR Specialist

Handling and ensuring proper maintenance of employees details and records.

Maintaining employee records on HRMS portals (Employwise and GreytHR) as well and keeping it up to date (Creating new joiners, updating personal details, uploading documents, processing exits).

Preparing of various required formats and letters such as Appointment letter, Confirmation letter, Promotion letter, Increment letter, Warning letter.

Scheduling and conducting the HR Induction programs for new joiners

Assist in the Development and implementation of human resource policies.

Issuance of employee ID cards and Medical cards to the employees and maintaining accurate records.

Organising monthly HR connect and quarterly fun activities for employees.

Developing and maintaining healthy employee relations and handling grievances thus creating an amicable & transparent work environment.

Registering the employee under ESIC scheme and sharing TIC to them.

Maintaining & Updating the Leave records and Attendance management.

Ensuring accuracy in attendance/ leaves records and calculations subject to payroll processing.

Providing payroll Inputs to the finance team on a monthly basis.

Supporting the team in projects and tasks when required.

Managing all the exit formalities of employees as per pre- defined Exit policy.

Indian Optics Pvt. Ltd.

23rd March 2021 - 12th April 2022

Sr. Executive- HR

Responsible for handling monthly payroll process and ensuring timely delivery of payroll.

Ensuring timelines are met for salary disbursement and statutory compliance.

Submitting Monthly challan for ESIC and PF on Gov Portal.

Supervise the implementation of worker's compensation programs and ensure legal compliance.

Planning manpower, vendor coordination, screening of CVs, conducting telephonic rounds and face-to-face interviews, scheduling interviews, conducting induction programs, etc.

Administering HR Operations- Appointment letter, Confirmation letter, Promotion letter, personal, full & final settlement, exit formalities, etc.

Enhancing job satisfaction and grievance handling.

Preparing employee remuneration transfer letter for bank.

Providing administrative support to the HR department.

Responsible for providing and maintaining the Mediclaim policy of employees.

Managing personal documentation and file maintenance of all employees.

IAPL Group Pvt. Ltd.

28th December 2017 - 28th February 2020

Executive Assistant HR

Daily personal handling and administration activities such as employee records and files.

Collecting, Calculating, and entering the data in order to maintain and update payroll information.

Preparing monthly salary sheet and PF attendance sheet.

Resolving employees grievances related to salary, ESI, PF, Leave, Attendance, Salary slip, etc.

Preparing of various required formats and letters for the HR department.

Assisting in the implementation of HR policies and procedures.

Interacting with Bank representatives for creating new employee's corporate accounts & Bank formalities.

Coordinating with the graphic designing department for the generation of employee ID cards and visiting cards.

Responsible for providing and maintaining the mediclaim policy of employees.

Coordinating with the Accounts department for timely payment of invoices.

Annually collecting the investment proofs from all employees and maintaining them.

Assisting our company advocate in drafting and preparing legal letters.

Registering fingerprints of new employees in Bio-metric device for Attendance.

Academic Qualification

- MBA in HRM and FM from Swami Vivekanand Subharti University in 2020
- B.Com from Delhi University in 2017
- 12th from CBSE Board in 2014
- 10th from CBSE Board in 2012

Online Course

• Time Management, Excel Tips & Ticks, Smart English basics for professional, Human Resource Management

Computer Proficiency

 Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Employwise, GreytHR, Tally ERP. 9.0, Outlook, Google Sheets, Google Docs.

Skills

 Adaptability, Communication skills, Organizational skills, Time Management, Multi-Tasking skills, Leadership Abilities.

Achievements & Awards

• Received Sport Award Certificate for exceptional HR support, professionalism, and dedication .

Personal Strength

Positive attitude towards work.
Honesty and punctuality towards every work.

Honesty and punctuality towards every work.

Honesty and punctuality towards every work.

Hard working with goal-oriented skills.

Ability to work in a team as well as individual

Eagerness to learn new technology and development.

Personal Details

Date of Birth : 07-Mar-1997
 Marital Status : Single
 Nationality : Indian

Language Known : English & Hindi